Albert Lockett

902-471-5147 albert.lockett@gmail.com https://github.com/albertlockett https://www.linkedin.com/in/albert-lockett-18770255/

Summary

Full stack software engineer with over 6 years professional experience building web applications, leading development teams, supporting operational teams, and assisting with data analytics engagements. Seeking role as software engineering role working with web related technologies and opportunity for mentorship.

Skills

- JavaScript React, Redux, Webpack, Jest, Enzyme, GraphQL Node, Express
- Java Spring Framework, GraphQL, JSP, JUnit, Hibernate
- Web HTML, CSS, SASS
- Database SQL: Oracle, MySQL; NoSQL: Elasticsearch, Redis
- Other Docker, Kubernetes, AWS
- Learning Typescript, Go

Experience

Senior Software Engineer, Sonrai Security

January 2018 - Present

- Worked on Frontend UX design and implementation using JavaScript, React, Redux, HTML, CSS
- Primary developer of backend GraphQL Server using Java, Spring Framework
- Worked with NoSQL databases including JanusGraph, Elasticsearch, Redis
- Wrote analytics jobs using Spark, executing on AWS EMR
- Automated Testing using JUnit, Jest, Enzyme
- Deployed on AWS using Docker, Kubernetes, EKS Service

Team Lead/Software Engineer - Ernst & Young Canada

June 2014 - December 2017

- Software engineering in a consulting capacity
- Worked as team lead for four engineers and three QA professionals
- Front-end UX design and implementation using React, Redux, React Router, Draft.js & SASS, Javascript, JSP, jQuery, HTML, CSS
- Backend API design and implementation using JavaScript with Node.js, GraphQL, express, Sequelize ORM and Java with Spring Framework, Hibernate ORM
- Setup docker based development environment and created custom images to improve build speed on Gitlab CI by 80%
- Automated testing using JUnit, Mocha, Chai, Enzyme, ChimpJS
- Worked with MySQL and Oracle databases

Software Engineer - Ambir Solutions

August 2013 - June 2014

- Software engineering in a consulting capacity
- Front-end application development using JSP, jQuery, Bootstrap
- Back-end application development using Java, Spring Framework, Struts
- Performed maintenance on J2EE based IVR system
- Wrote stored procedures and schema migration scripts for Oracle database

Customer Solutions Engineering Support - Bell Aliant

May 2010 - September 2012 (Summers only during university)

- Supported enterprise sales engineering team at regional telco
- Initiated orders for VLAN and firewall configuration changes on Cisco and Juniper appliances
- Wrote code using C to automate lookup of network circuit configurations in internal systems
- Supported sales efforts by visiting clients and gathering requirements

Education

Bachelors of Computer Engineering September 2009 - May 2013 University of New Brunswick